So now the plan is
either find ourselves
a new counselor,
stick it out with the old one,
but go more often,
or resign ourselves to the fact
that she's never gonna be happy...
no matter what I do, so let's take
the money we're wasting and put it
towards a membership at Lakeview.
[Chuckles] I'm guessing the last
option has yet to be formally presented.
Yeah.
Geez. What's with you?
You usually run half speed
to stay with me.
Didn't get a lot of sleep last night.
[Panting]
How are things with Elyse?
Great.
Great?
Yeah.
One-syllable answers.
You're either out of breath,
or you're lying to me.
Yeah. We have our moments,
but they usually work out.
Man, you got some water?
Yeah.
So how do you work things out?
I don't know.
We talk, someone apologizes.
Man, I shouldn't have
drank last night.
- Hey, you mean you apologize.
- Yeah, I guess.
- How often do you guys have sex?
- Enough.
You do it this morning?
You did.
You did it this morning.
[Chuckles]
Maybe that's why
you can't stand up, huh? Come on.
[Panting]
Elyse.
Great.
Honey, I'm dehydrated.
Do we have anything
with electrolytes?
Sleeping Beauty, wake up.
[Sighs]
This is an emergency.
The fridge is empty.
[Murmurs]
Come on.
It's almost 4:00.
[Murmuring]
Elyse. Sweetie.
CallJacques.
Tell him I'm not feeling well.
It's Saturday.
You haven't been to work
in three days. Remember?
Just let me sleep.
Come on.
You haven't been out of bed
since Wednesday.
- Leave me alone.
- Come on. What's up?
No. Leave me alone.
Honey.
I said leave me alone!
Oh. I think there's
something wrong with me.
She's been averaging 18 hours of sleep
a day since her admission.
Clinical depression.
Incredibly contagious.
Every time I'm around
one of them, I get blue.
It's not clinical depression.
Great.
Got it all figured out.
You don't need me.
Three E.R. Doctors, two neurologists
and a radiologist have all
figured out what it's not.
We need to figure out what it is.
If any of the above-mentioned
doctors...
were interested in my opinion,
they would have asked for it.
None of them are willing
to subject themselves to you.
No pain, no gain.
[Elevator Bell Dings]
The blood work shows
no signs of inflammation,
and no one can figure out
what's actually the cause-
Ah.
What?
Husband described her as being
unusually irritable recently.
And?
I didn't realize it was possible for
a woman to be unusually irritable.
[Elevator Bell Dings]
Nice try, but you're a misanthrope,
not a misogynist.
What's the first thing
you ask a doctor
who's referring a patient?
Are you questioning my ability
to take a history?
What's the primary-
Not "what." "Why?"
Diseases don't
have motives.
No, but doctors do.
Why this patient?
What interests you?
Give me the chart.
Why?
Lfind your interest interesting.
[House]
She's irritable and sleeping
18 hours a day.
What's interesting about that?
Hypersomnia's usually accompanied
by irritability in depressed patients.
True, but not relevant.
She's not depressed.
Hello. She's sleeping
18 hours a day.
Fever.
Clinical depression
does not cause fever.
- She could be sick and depressed.
- She's sick.
Oh, damn it.
Why didn't I think of that?
- Yeah, that's what I meant.
- Elevated sed rate indicates inflammation.
Hypersomnia and personality changes
point toward the brain.
Not the spleen?
Thank goodness we hired
a neurologist.
Brain symptoms. Hmm.
Could this be a brain problem?
No other systemic signs of inflammation.
Probably not vasculitis.
What about parasites?
Malaria, Chagas.
But the patient's never been outside of
the United States- especially the tropics.
- You mean she claims
she's never been outside the U.S.
- Very good.
Doesn't matter.
Blood and C.S.F. Smears
show no sign of parasites.
- Has to be a tumor then.
- A tumor sitting directly
on top of the brain stem...
that three E.R. Doctors,
two neurologists
and a radiologist missed?
Partridge in a pear tree
missed it too.
Redo the blood work, and get a new M.R.I.
With two-millimeter cuts
through the mesodiencephalic.
And check for evil stepmothers.
This much sleep
usually indicates poison apples.
Anything else besides
the shortness ofbreath?
Not really.
It's actually just kind of a tightness.
You smoke?
No, never.
- Exercise?
- Eight hours a day.
- I teach preschool.
- Sounds fun.
Any history of heart disease
in your family?
Not that I know of.
Take a deep breath.
Been under
a lot of stress lately?
No more than usual.
You're probably just a little anemic.
I'm gonna do an E.K.G.
Just to make sure.
Do I need to take this off?
Uh, no. You can just
pull that down in front.
Good Lord.
- Are those real?
- Do they look real?
They look pretty damn good.
They were a present
for my husband's 40th.
Lfigured he'd enjoy them
more than a sweater.
That's so sweet.
But I'm afraid the cause of your problem
could be staring us right in the face.
Actually, I guess
I'm the one doing the staring.
Of course, I can't be sure.
I'd like to consult a colleague.
He's actually somewhat
of an expert in these matters.
Can I get a page on Dr. Wilson?
A tumor?
We don't know.
- We're checking just to be safe.
- Y'all already checked for that.
The previous M.R.I. Had a broader view.
Some tumors are almost impossible to see
unless you know exactly where to look.
- That means it would be small, right?
- Yeah.
Then you'd be able
to operate, take it out?
If it's a tumor, there are
a variety of treatment options,
but there are variables
other than just size.
Don't worry.
Too late.
[Chuckles Nervously]
Try to remain as still as possible.
The less distortion there is,
the more detail we'll be able to see.
Okay.
[Man On P.A.]
X-ray tech, report to Radiology Room 3.
Well. That's what
breasts look like.
Is a lie a lie
if everybody knows it's a lie?
Well, if a tree pretends
to fall in a forest-
House, come on. They're breasts.
They're a birthday present,
not a philosophical treatise.
Lie number one.
She did not do that for her husband.
She did that for herself.
She thinks if she looks different,
she'll be different.
No. She thinks if she looks different,
she'll be more attractive,
which I have to say-
Not to her husband.
Cosmetic surgery is so everyone else
will look at us differently.
The same reason
you're wearing that tie.
Well, exactly.
That was gonna be my next point.
Last three months,
same five ties.
Thursday should be
that paisley thing.
It's a gift from my wife.
No, it's not.
Julie hates green.
You bought that yourself.
You want to look pretty at work.
[Singsong]
Wilson's got a girlfriend.
D- Stop.
Stop. I don't.
It takes two department heads
to treat shortness of breath?
What, do the complications
increase exponentially with cup size?
I want an E.K.G. And blood tests,
including tox screen on Mrs. -
- Exam Room One.
- You're ordering tests
to cover your lechery.
- Interesting.
- Very tricky case.
You love everybody.
That's your pathology.
There were no lesions
and no mass effect that we could see.
What does that mean?
It means we're still not sure
what's causing
the neurological problems.
I know some things are hard to cure,
but what I just don't get
is why it's taking so long
to figure out what's wrong with her.
- I know you're scared.
I would be too.
- I don't feel good.
You feeling nauseous?
Honey, are you all right?
[Cameron]
She's seizing.!
Get her on her side.
- I need some Ativan!
- [Nurse]
I'll get it.
- What's happened?
- She's having a seizure.
- [Gagging]
- She's aspirating. Suction.
[Gagging]
[Cameron]
Come on, Elyse.
[Gagging Continues]
[Wilson]
The M.R.I. Reveals nothing.
- [Foreman]
That we were able to detect.
- It's not a tumor.
A small glioma
could hide from contrast.
We could do a PETscan.
Yes. That's how a responsible doctor
would waste his time in this situation.
Suddenly tests and radiologists
are incapable of error?
A glioma not presenting
on a contrast M.R.I. Would have to be
smaller than a grain of sand,
which does not
a gravely ill person make.
- It could be just postictal disorientation.
- We would have seen
improvement by now.
- Late-stage Lyme disease
can cause seizures.
- Does the husband care about her?
- He hasn't left her bedside.
- How annoying.
It also means
she doesn't have Lyme disease.
What, love conquers all?
Lyme disease initially presents
with a rash.
- Mr. Clingy would have noticed.
- We've looked at everything else.
Did you look at her breasts?
[Scoffs]
Men.
It could be paraneoplastic.
She have any family history
of breast cancer?
Her mother died of it.
The brain, but not the brain.
Clever, huh?
How can breast cancer
cause problems in her brain?
There are molecular similarities
between brain cells and tumor cells.
Paraneoplastic syndrome
causes the body's own antibodies
to get thrown off track.
They end up attacking the brain
instead of the tumor.
So, if you do find a tumor,
what do you do?
We treat the underlying malignancy.
Once there's no tumor to attack,
there's nothing for the antibodies
to get confused about.
- If the tumor's treatable.
- Exactly.
[Beeping]
Ow.
I'm sorry.
I know it's uncomfortable.
The tighter we go,
the better the image will be.
[Whirring]
At least it'll keep me awake.
Don't worry. It's almost over.
I wish people would stop
telling me not to worry.
[Click]
I'm sorry.
My mom was the same age.
[Keypad Beeping]
[Beep]
We've been trying
to get pregnant for over a year.
Guess we're lucky we didn't.
A lot has changed
since your mom died.
Don't worr-
Don't give up.
[Keypad Beeps]
[House]
No tumor?
The M.R.I. And the mammogram
only showed a few benign calcifications.
It's most likely a small-cell tumor.
It's no surprise
we're having trouble finding it.
We should do a PET scan.
Start with her lungs,
then maybe her bones.
Sometimes it presents
with no tumor at all.
- How can a disease caused by a tumor
present if there's no tumor?
- It happens- 12% of cases.
- And how do you treat it
if there's no tumor?
- You don't.
Those 12%, no treatment.
They were too busy
looking for the tumor-
right till they put the patient
in the ground.
- What choice do we have?
- Treat the symptoms.
- I.V. Immunoglobulin.
- So we're just gonna ignore the tumor?
Well, eventually it'll get bigger.
Then it'll be really easy to find.
- One of you needs to check out
where she works.
- Why?
- 'Cause the husband's not sick.
- [Chase]
Meaning?
If it's not paraneoplastic,
and it is a reaction
to some sort of toxin,
it's obviously not
coming from their home.
Foreman, you do it.
Why are you riding me?
It's what I do.
Has it got worse lately?
Yeah. Seems to me.
Really?
Well, that rules out the race thing.
'Cause you were just as black last week.
How long has Elyse worked here?
Oh, three years.
She's my best rotisseur.
And what's that?
The rotisseur prepares
the roasted meats and gravies.
How do you clean your grill?
[Chuckles, Speaks French]
You say "elbow grease."
Do you use chemical cleaners?
Ah, non. Absolument.
And chefs don't do the cleaning anyway.
What about pesticides?
You must spray for roaches
and that sort of thing.
No. My kitchen is clean.
No roaches.
[Speaking French]
[French]
I need to get back to work.
So the fact that I'm here
asking you these questions,
it doesn't worry you?
[Chuckles]
Look at me.
I'm here 18 hours a day.
That guy practically lives here.
He does live here.
I use the same detergents
for 15 years, and everyone
is healthy as a horse.
Whatever Elyse has,
she didn't get here.
Tell her I hope
she feels better.
And I had to get a new rotisseur.
- Where's Ed?
- He went down to the gift shop
to buy a shirt.
I told him I'd stay up here
in case you woke up.
You must have better things to do.
I send my laundry out.
- You're not married?
- No.
Waiting for the perfect guy?
Let me guess.
You've already found him.
He threw my towels out the window.
[Chuckles]
That's how we met.
Freshman year, Ed came to a party
that my roommate and I threw.
He spent most of the night
on the bathroom floor.
He figured I wouldn't notice
the vomit on the towels
if I didn't have any towels.
I'm assuming he came back
the next day to apologize?
No way.
I had to track him down.
[Sighs]
Conflict resolution has never
been one of Ed's strong points.
Nobody's perfect, right?
I guess.
Oh, my neck hurts.
You've been in this bed
for a really long time.
We're gonna do the same test
we did last night, okay?
Do you know what day it is?
My arm itches.
It's probably a mild skin irritation.
I'll get you some hydrocortisone in a minute.
- Do you know what day it is?
- Tuesday.
It really itches.
How about I get you
that cream right now?
Oh, my God! Get them off!
Get 'em off of me!
- Get 'em off me! Get 'em off me!
- Elyse, calm down.
- Get them off me!
- Elyse, calm down. Calm down.
They're biting me!
Oh! They're biting me!
I'm gonna need some Haldol,
five milligrams.
- Honey, what's wrong?
- Get 'em off!
Get 'em off. Get 'em off.
There's nothing there, Elyse.
They're biting me.
There's nothing there.
Ow!
[Foreman]
We had to sedate her.
You gave sedatives to a patient
who's already sleeping
18 hours a day?
It was better than letting her
scratch all the skin off her arms.
- Where's Wilson?
- Creepy-crawlies are consistent
with paraneoplastic syndrome.
Onset immediately after
I.V.I.G. Isn't.
There is a simple explanation.
Maybe she really has
bugs under her skin.
- Infection?
- That's what a worsening of symptoms
after immunotherapy would suggest.
Blood cultures and the timeline
rule out most bacteria.
Patient throws up on your shoes,
do you clean up most of it?
The symptoms rule out the rest.
Serology rules out viruses.
C.S.F. Smears rule out parasites.
In the final stage
of African trypanosomiasis...
almost all the parasites
are inside the brain.
It's possible
they wouldn't show on smears.
But it's not possible for a patient
who's never been to Africa
to have African sleeping sickness.
- I'm just saying it fits the symptoms.
- She could've got it from a transfusion.
- Or I'm just saying she could've
got it from a transfusion.
- Which she never had.
Okay.
[Wilson]
What about toxins?
No, the kitchen she works in
is cleaner than some hospitals.
But they do serve rabbit.
Rabbit fever fits her symptoms.
Tularemia initially presents
with a rash or ulcer near the infection site.
Not if she inhaled it.
Chopping the meat with the cleaver
could easily aerosolize the bacteria.
- No. Then she'd have respiratory symptoms.
- Maybe she ignored it,
figured she had a cold.
We rejected Lyme disease because
the couple would have noticed a rash,
but a wet, hacking cough
is just gonna slip right by?
It's either that or she missed her exit
on the turnpike and wound up in Africa.
Okay, two lousy ideas.
Unfortunately, they're better
than all the other ideas.
Tularemia. Bizarre.
Very nice.
That's why I ride you.
[Man On TV]
Stay tuned-
Did he just turn on the TV?
He needs to think.
So this should tell us
whether or not she's got rabbit fever?
For a diagnosis of tularemia
you need a fourfold increase
in serum antibody levels.
To measure an increase you need a before.
All we have is an after.
- A single titer over 160
would be a big clue.
- "That's why I ride you."
What does that mean?
When I have a good idea
it's because ofhim?
Actually, I think he said
your idea was a lousy idea.
It has to be one of these two conditions.
I say we take our best guess
and start treatment. Or treat both.
The treatment for tularemia
can cause aplastic anemia.
- How come he doesn't ride you guys?
- Got a crush on you.
- He just doesn't know how to show it.
- Get over it. He rides everybody.
- The treatment for sleeping sickness
kills one in 10 patients.
- We start with the safer treatment.
By "safer," you mean the one
that's slightly less likely to kill her.
Foreman got the gang
testing for tularemia?
- Yep.
- Probably inconclusive, but worth doing.
So, what's her name?
When do I get to meet her?
- There's nobody.
Give it up.
- Your lips say no.
Your shoes say yes.
Well, they're French.
- You can't trust a word they say.
- Solid, yet stylish.
A professional woman
would be impressed.
I'm thinking accountant.
Actuary maybe.
It's somebody in the hospital.
Patient?
No. Chemo's not sexy.
Daughter of a patient.
She would certainly have
the neediness you need.
I'm not gonna date
a patient's daughter.
Very ethical.
Of course, most married men
would say they don't date at all.
There was no date.
I had lunch with one of the nurses.
It's her first time in an oncology unit.
She's having a tough time- emotionally.
- Perfect.
- I wanted to be nice.
That's all.
I mean it.
You always do.
It's part of your charm.
Hi, boys.
Mrs. Campbell's test results.
You remember her.
The preschool teacher
with the heart of silicone.
No. Doesn't ring a bell.
They came in yesterday. I figured you guys
would have been all over them.
I know how concerned you were.
She's all upset 'cause we paid
more attention to the other girl.
You check out her ass.
I've got the chest.
The tests were normal.
Of course, that's just my opinion.
You might wanna call a couple of guys
from maintenance in for a consult.
You check her E.K.G. Results
before she left the other day?
- You ordered it.
- You're the responsible one.
- What's wrong?
They look normal to me.
- Where is she?
- Waiting downstairs. Why?
- I was right.
Do I have to get rid of the implants?
Surprisingly, no.
But your E.K.G. Shows
a slightly decreased heart rate.
Is that a problem?
You told me you hadn't changed
your diet or exercise. Were you lying?
Lying?
Does your husband have
high blood pressure?
My husband?
Yeah, you see,
if you're gonna repeat
everything I say, this conversation's
gonna take twice as long.
Yes. He was diagnosed
six months ago.
He do a lot of cooking?
Not really, other than oatmeal
in the morning.
Did you happen to notice
a slightly odd taste
to the oatmeal lately?
Wait. Are you saying that-
That it looks like your husband...
stirred in some of
his blood pressure medication
along with the brown sugar.
You think my husband's
trying to poison me?
No. Nothing like that.
He just doesn't
want to have sex with you.
Decreased sex drive is one of
the most common side effects
of the beta-blockers he's been taking.
I'm guessing he figured
if you're both frigid, no harm, no foul.
Should've gotten him the sweater.
That's ridiculous.
Fine. But if you're still concerned
about the shortness of breath,
I'd start making your own breakfast.
Wait.
What should I do?
If you care about your husband at all,
I'd do the responsible thing.
Buy yourself some condoms,
go to a bar, find-
Huh.
[Beep]
Lab tests inconclusive?
Not surprisingly.
No. But too bad.
Luckily, I have the answer.
- To what?
- Thanks for asking.
To life itself: Sex. Anything that can be
transmitted via the blood
can be transmitted through sex.
- Sleeping sickness from sex?
- It's not without precedent.
I'm pretty sure it is, unless you're
talking about going to Africa
and having sex with a tsetse fly.
A Portuguese man
was diagnosed three years ago
with C.N.S. -affected sleeping sickness.
His only connection with Africa
was through a girlfriend
who'd served with the military in Angola.
Boy. Where'd you find that?
TheJournal of the Instituto
de Higiene e Medicina Tropical.
- You don't read Portuguese?
- You do?
Pretty sure that's what it said.
Either that or it was
an ad for sunglasses.
Her husband has never
been to Africa either.
Oh, stymied again.
Your logic is bulletproof.
I think ignoring respiratory symptoms
is more likely than cheating.
Because?
They're completely
devoted to each other.
Because?
They love each other.
Or?
They're overcompensating for guilt.
- Find out which it is.
- You want me to ask a man whose wife
is about to die if he cheated on her?
No, I want you to be polite
and let her die.
Actually, I don't want you
to ask her anything. Foreman,
take the husband. Chase, take the wife.
You don't trust me to do my job?
We all formulate questions based on
the answers we want to hear.
And how exactly do you reformulate
"Have you screwed around?"
Did you know she's been
trying to get pregnant?
Yes.
After you got so freaked
about the sick babies a while ago,
lfigured that was your thing.
But you've never been prescribed
folic acid, and you can't lose a baby
if you've never been pregnant.
You pulled my medical records?
You coughed the other day.
I was concerned.
You were curious, like an eight-year-old boy
with a puzzle that's just a little too
grown-up for him to figure out.
Tomayto, tomahto.
So it's either, uh, sleeping sickness
or this rabbit thing?
They're both fatal without treatment.
And unfortunately, the treatment
for both is extremely dangerous.
Are there tests you can do?
Not at this stage.
But each condition has a unique history.
We're hoping your answers
to a few questions will help us.
Sure. Whatever you need to know.
Before the sleeping problems,
did you have any trouble breathing,
a cough that wouldn't go away-
anything like that?
No.
Are you certain?
[Ed]
Absolutely.
I've never been away from her
for more than a night.
If she had breathing troubles
I would've noticed.
The other condition is
significantly more likely if-
if you've had an affair.
Have you ever had an affair?
Of course not.
- Are you sure?
- I think I'd remember
cheating on my wife.
You might be
reluctant to admit it.
No.
I just want to be perfectly clear.
If your wife has sleeping sickness,
and we don't treat her,
she'll die.
I would never do that to Ed.
I love him.
[Ed]
Absolutely not.
I love her.
All right.
All right then.
They say no cheating,
we cross off sleeping sickness.
Any new ideas?
Okay. We go with Foreman's tularemia.
Start her on I.V. Chloramphenicol,
25 milligrams per kilogram,
four times a day.
Good night.
[Machine Beeping]
Where's Ed?
Right next to you.
Well, you're two down,
two to go.
Two days?
No. Doses. You have about
20 more days of this fun.
What time is it?
About 4:00 a.m.
I pulled the short straw.
Flow rate looks good.
No rash or flushing.
What time is it?
4:00 a.m.
Do you not remember just asking?
I don't-
Elyse?
Elyse? Elyse?
- Elyse.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to wake her.
- She fall asleep again?
In the middle of a sentence.
Elyse. Elyse.
- [Man]
What's happening?
- Patient's not responding.
Pulse is fine.
Airway's open.
Check her blood pressure.
Pupils are reactive.
Elyse, wake up.
You gotta wake up.
- What does that mean?
What are you doing?
- She's unresponsive to pain.
Come on, Elyse.
- Is she dying?
- I don't know.
She's in a coma.
There's only one way
a tularemia patient
goes into a coma...
while on I.V. Chloramphenicol.
The patient doesn't have tularemia.
And then there was one.
Patient comes in
'cause she's sleeping too much.
It takes 10 doctors and a coma
to diagnose sleeping sickness.
And then there was none.
We still have the problem
of explaining how
a white chick from Jersey...
who's never traveled south of D.C.
Has African sleeping sickness.
Still have the obvious explanation.
I made it clear.
If this guy's lying about sleeping around
he knows he's murdering his wife.
Does seem unlikely.
Go away.
[Beeping]
What are you doing?
Checking for lymphadenopathy.
And waiting for you.
Who are you?
I'm Dr. House.
Your wife has
human African trypanosomiasis.
Sleeping sickness.
You mean it's not tularemia,
a virus, tumor or- or cancer?
No.
I've never had an affair.
I believe you.
And I trust Elyse.
The treatment for this disease
is a drug that's...
fatal on its own 10% of the time.
Which is why I need
your written consent
before I can legally prescribe it.
Why would she lie
if she knew it could kill her?
I don't ask why patients lie.
I just assume they all do.
But why?
To protect you,
because she didn't think it mattered,
it just seemed easier, because...
that's what people do.
If you're absolutely certain
that your wife has never
had sex with anyone but you...
since you were married,
then I'm wrong.
But if you think there's
a possibility that just one time...
she wasn't perfect-
one weekend you're out of town,
one fight where she ran to a friend,
one stupid Christmas party-
then you need to allow me
to start treatment.
Because if we don't,
she's gonna be dead
by tomorrow morning.
You trust your wife that much?
I don't know.
I'm gonna start the treatment.
Glass syringes?
And special I.V. Tubing.
Why do we need this stuff?
Because melarsoprol melts plastic.
This stuff's basically arsenic
mixed with antifreeze.
What doesn't kill us
makes us stronger, huh?
Nietzsche wouldn't have been so glib
if he'd been prescribed melarsoprol.
"Can cause vomiting, abdominal pain,
blood toxicity, neural damage,
cardiac arrhythmia."
They forgot to say
it's gonna hurt like all hell.
[Foreman]
She's lucky she's in a coma.
How long before we know
if it's working?
It's tough to say.
It's a good sign
that she hasn't gotten any worse.
Does she even know I'm here?
She knows you're
always there for her.
Yeah.
If she gets better,
it means she wasn't always there for me.
It means she made a mistake.
I can't help it.
Part of me- a big part of me-
can't handle that.
It doesn't want her to get better.
Does that make me
a terrible person?
Yes.
[Elevator Bell Dings]
So you're treating her
for African sleeping sickness...
because you don't think it's possible
for someone to be faithful
in a relationship?
And you do?
Yes.
And you need to tell me that.
[Chuckles]
Look. I am not having an affair.
I had lunch with someone
I work with- at work. Once.
I believe you.
What I don't believe
is it'll be just once.
I love my wife.
You certainly love saying it.
[Chuckles]
I'm sorry.
I know you love your wife.
You loved all your wives.
Probably still do.
In fact, you probably love
all the women you loved
who weren't your wife.
You can be a real jerk sometimes,
you know that?
Yeah. And you're the good guy.
At least I try.
As long as you're trying to be good,
you can do whatever you want.
And as long as you're not trying,
you can say whatever you want.
So, between us, we can do anything.
We can rule the world.
[Sighs]
Mixing up some margaritas?
Mine's a double, senorita.
That's Portuguese, you know.
Spanish.
Uh-oh.
What's goin' on?
I'm recalibrating the centrifuge.
Turn around.
It's a very sad thing.
An uncalibrated centrifuge.
Makes me cry too.
I'm not crying.
Okay.
I told the husband he was a jerk.
Why?
When I was in college, l-
I fell in love,
and I got married.
And-
At that age, the chances
of marriage lasting-
It lasted six months.
Thyroid cancer
metastasized to his brain.
There was nothing they could do.
I was 21, and...
I watched my husband die.
I'm sorry.
But that's not the whole story.
It's a symptom, not your illness.
Thyroid cancer would have been
diagnosed at least a year before his death.
You knew he was dying
when you married him.
It must have been
when you first met him.
And you married him anyway.
You can't be that good a person
and well-adjusted.
Why?
'Cause you wind up
crying over centrifuges.
Or hating people?
[Pager Beeping]
[Chase]
Her fever spiked at 104.
Echo shows global hyperkinesis.
Blood pressure?
Barely 90 over 40.
Did you give her dopamine?
Started 270 micrograms
per minute 10 minutes ago.
Still no change.
Killing the parasites
isn't gonna do much good
if we kill her heart at the same time.
A heart can be replaced.
A brain can't.
Right now we're killing both.
If she's gonna die, we should at least
let her do it without that acid
flowing through her veins.
What's happening?
We would've expected
your wife's condition to show
some improvement by now.
It hasn't.
It's going the other way.
Please don't die.
[Beeping]
[Beeping Speed Increases]
She's awake.
Hey. She's gonna be okay.
Yeah. Sure.
What are you gonna do?
Were you always honest with her?
Do you know how lucky you are?
Your wife is alive. She loves you.
What she did-
You can't love a person
and do that to them.
She loves you.
[Sobbing]
I need to know
who you had the affair with.
He has to be notified
so he can get treatment as well.
Why did you lie to us?
You knew your life was at stake.
He's not coming back, is he?
We all make mistakes,
and we all pay a price.
I need that name.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
Hey, there.
How you doin'?
Fine.
Do you know where your dad is?
Can I help you?
That's some bad hat, Harry.
www.tvsubtitles.net